( man ) Mother , Father , what 's afoot ?
Only Possum , black as soot .
Mother , Father , where to tread ?
Far from Possum and his head .
Here 's a bag , now what 's inside ?
Does he seek or does he hide ?
Can you spy him , deep within ?
Little Possum , black as sin .
- ( boy 1 ) Did you hear about it ? - ( boy 2 ) I know where that happened .
( boy 1 ) Where ?
- ( boy 3 ) He doesn 't know . - ( boy 2 ) All right .
- ( boy 1 ) Where , then ? - ( boy 2 ) Fallmarsh Woods .
( boy 3 ) Liar . They ain 't even said who it was .
- Besides , it was the old army barracks . - ( boy 1 ) Whereabouts ?
( boy 2 ) Fallmarsh Woods , the police said .
( boy 3 ) Liar .
( boy 2 ) Well , my uncle told me , and his neighbour 's a policeman .
( boy 1 ) Bollocks is he .
- ( boy 2 ) He knows all about you . - ( boys laugh )
( boy 1 ) Whoa , whoa , whoa . Stop ! Why you hittin ' me ? Stop .
- Stop , both of you . Stop . - ( driver ) Fallmarsh , next stop .
What were you drawing ?
( lock turns )
( shuts door )
Maurice ?
( clattering )
( man ) Bag is open , growing wider .
What 's inside , man or spider ?
Little boy , don 't lose your way .
Possum wants to come and play .
( water runs )
( turns off tap )
( man ) Going in ?
No .
Mind of its own ?
The legs are impressive .
- What exactly is it ? - It 's a puppet .
You show that to children ?
- ( pours tea ) - I 'm destroying it .
Even the head ?
I heard about your performance .
An old teaching colleague of mine wrote to me .
A scandal , by all accounts .
They 'll take me back , once that 's gone .
( spits )
Now you won 't get something from the jar .
May I have a demonstration ?
I wanna see how the legs work .
Before you kill it .
Can 't kill it , it 's a puppet .
Burn it , will you ?
This place is disgusting , Maurice .
King of the castle .
Remember , a demonstration .
( man ) Look at Possum , there he lies .
Children , meet his lifeless eyes .
See his nasty legs and tongue .
When he wakens , watch him run .
( man in distance ) Philip !
( Maurice ) Come in .
I want to borrow the tools .
Please ?
- Hungry ? - No .
Roast fox .
Funny .
Dismantling it , are you ?
- In my own time , yeah . - Pity .
Puppetry 's the one thing you were good at .
Staying , are you ?
For a while . My house .
Remember this one ?
Well made .
My father taught me , you know .
- Runs in the family . - You 're not my father , Maurice .
Bring ' em back .
( white noise )
( woman on TV ) Police are investigating the disappearance of a 14-year-old boy
near Fullmarsh , in Norfolk .
Officers are searching local woodlands and waste ground
in an effort to find the teenager ,
who was last seen on his way home from Marshwood Secondary School
- in the area of Full ... - ( white noise )
( turns off TV )
Is that you , pervert ?
Come on .
( teacher ) Can I ask what you 're doing ?
Nothing .
Why are you waiting there ?
Used to be my school .
Move on , will you ?
Yes , sir . Sorry , sir .
( Philip exhales )
- ( man in distance ) Philip ! - ( Philip gasps )
( breathes heavily )
( Philip ) Wait awhile , my little child , for what is playing dead .
Possum , with his black balloons , will eat you up in bed .
Waking up , is it ?
Wants to get out .
Something from the jar ?
What 's in them ?
Same as always .
No , then .
All grown up now .
Tell me again about the fox .
Why ?
Why not ?
No .
Tell me .
We were on the marshes ,
me and the other boys .
I 'd built a den there .
Out by the bridges there .
I wanted to show ' em .
When we got there , we found a fox .
Thought it had swallowed something , ' cause it was pantin ' .
Whole body was shakin ' like it was dyin ' .
They started to kick it .
All of ' em . Yeah .
Kicked it around like it was a ball ...
Then stuck things in it , till it was dead .
Then what ?
Wanted me to pick it up .
Made me .
They grabbed my head ,
pushed my face inside where it was rotten .
I started to cry .
They laughed .
Ran off and left me .
And then after a while ...
the fox ...
opened its eyes and stared at me .
Stood up and walked away .
There .
( chuckles )
( laughs )
( coughs )
Sly bugger .
Playin ' with ya .
Yours , I believe .
Like this house , Maurice .
They 're demolishing the old barracks .
About bloody time .
Black as sin , it is .
Going in ?
( door opens )
( breathes heavily )
( gasps )
Maurice ?
( Maurice in the distance ) " Possum . How he came into the world . 1978 . "
" By Philip Connell . "
( Maurice in the distance ) " After the fire . Possum . "
" Was it he who blackened the very sun above our town ? "
" Possum . Does his stare not seem like the face of waking death ? "
" Behold how he came into the world . "
" Mother , Father , what 's afoot ? Only Possum , black as soot . "
( Maurice 's voice grows louder ) " Mother , Father , where to tread ? "
" Far from Possum and his head . "
" Wait awhile , my little child , for what is playing dead . "
( Maurice 's voice grows louder ) " Possum , with his black balloons ,
will eat you up in bed . "
" Look at Possum , there he lies . "
" Children , meet his lifeless eyes . "
" See his nasty legs and tongue . When he wakens , watch him run . "
" Here 's a bag , now what 's inside ? "
" Does he seek , or does he hide ? "
" Can you spy him , deep within ? "
" Little Possum , black as sin . "
" Bag is open , growing wider . "
" What 's inside it ,
man or spider ? "
" Little boy , don 't lose your way . "
" Possum wants to come and play . "
- Where 'd you get that ? - Fell . From there .
Liar .
( chuckles )
( laughs )
( laughs loudly )
Didn 't know you could draw as well .
Private .
Is it dead yet ?
Mind your own business .
( Maurice ) Perhaps it 's still playin ' .
- You won 't see me again , Maurice . - Won 't I ?
Train line 's down .
Home for the holidays , you are .
But I 'd watch where you 're treadin ' , lad .
- People are talkin ' . - Talkin ' about what ?
Don 't you read the papers ?
Why didn 't you burn , Maurice , eh ?
Hmm ?
Why wasn 't it you ?
( chuckles )
( laughs )
( continues laughing )
( coughs )
Maurice ?
( runs upstairs )
( Philip ) Happy valley , painted black , all the children in a sack .
Wave goodbye to sun and moon .
Say hello to black balloon .
Happened before , I recall .
Your time . After the fire .
Your school , wasn 't it ?
I taught you there once , remember ?
- I remember . - That business with the fox ...
A colleague asked me in to teach them all a lesson .
Remember their faces .
We showed ' em , didn 't we ?
Petrified , they were .
Stuffed ' em inside a bag , didn 't he ?
Wore a mask so they couldn 't see him .
There , there , lad .
I had no idea .
I 'm sorry . Here .
( Philip whimpers )
- ( Maurice ) I had no idea . - ( gags )
( gags )
( breathes heavily )
( knocking at door )
( knocking continues )
( car engine starts )
( car drives away )
Maurice ?
( white noise on TV )
( woman 's voice on TV )
( white noise )
( woman on TV ) Police are widening their search
for missing teenager Michael Browning
who disappeared on his way home from school on Tuesday afternoon .
Officers are investigating reports of a man acting suspiciously
near woodlands and waste ground , close to a former military barracks
in the area of Fullmarsh .
The suspect , who was wearing a beige raincoat ,
was seen several times with a boy matching Michael 's description .
Police are warning members of the public not to approach the man ,
and urge anyone with information to contact the police on this number ...
( Maurice ) What are you lookin ' for ?
I wanna talk to you .
- ( Philip knocks ) - ( Maurice ) Come .
Someone come ' ere for you .
Who ?
Law , I reckon .
- What did they want ? - None of my business .
Said you were out .
Did you find him ?
- Who ? - Who you 're lookin ' for .
- No . - He 'll turn up . They always do .
We burnt it .
You and me , we burnt it , the puppet .
You look confused , lad .
You don 't look well .
Your face .
Maybe you best lie low for a while .
I 'm goin ' away .
Where you goin ' ?
My business .
You 'll have this place to yourself .
Don 't bring trouble home .
Bloody kids .
( woman ) Wait there , please .
Can I see him then , please , miss ? Will I ... Will I see him , Mr Grant ?
He 's my form teacher .
He knows all about it . He knows what 's happened .
Said he 'd come with me .
- Come where ? - Police station , miss .
Wait there , please .
( indistinct talking )
( man ) OK , will you call them ? And I 'll keep him here .
( Maurice ) The parcel opened , out it sprang ,
the black long-legged Possum man .
Children , run ! He 'll eat and smother any child without a mother .
( Philip ) Maurice !
Maurice !
( Philip breathes heavily )
( clattering )
Maurice !
( whimpers )
- ( thud ) - ( groans )
- ( thud ) - ( screams )
No , no , no !
No !
( gasps )
( exhales )
( Philip yells )
( Philip moans )
( breathes heavily )
- Come to see Mummy and Daddy ? - No , no , no .
- ( groans ) No . - Dirty boy .
- ( Philip ) No . No . - Playing with the dead .
( whimpers ) No .
- No . ( groans ) No , no , no . - Poor boy .
Poor orphan boy .
- Mummy and Daddy all burned away ? - No .
There , there . Uncle 's here , lad . Uncle Maurice with his fingers .
( whines ) No .
No !
No ... No , no , no .
- ( Maurice ) Do you like my fingers , boy ? - No .
Have you missed them ?
Please ... Please , Uncle Maurice , don 't . Please , don 't .
Do you want my fingers , you dirty , filthy boy ?
No !
Open up , then !
( groans )
Open up , I said !
( gags )
- Filthy boy . - ( Philip moans )
Leave home , would ya ?
Leave your poor , wicked uncle all alone ?
- ( groans ) No , please . - Poor Philip .
Poor , broken Philip .
All grown up .
( Philip whines ) No ! No .
- Home for a hidin ' . - No .
- Turn over . - No , Maurice . No .
- Trousers down . - No . No !
You knew it was me , didn 't you , boy ? Out by the barracks .
You knew it was me ... ( shouts ) Didn 't ya ?
- Yes . - It 's where I worked .
Worked everywhere , I have .
But you said nothing . Silly boy .
Now they 're huntin ' you .
- Now you 'll get what 's comin ' . - ( groans )
- Six of the best , then . - No !
( yells )
- If you cry , I 'll start again . - ( moans )
- ( yells ) - If you cry , I 'll start again .
- ( muffled scream ) - One !
- ( muffled scream ) - Two !
- ( thudding ) - Three !
( belt cracks )
- ( Maurice ) Four ! - ( thudding )
- ( Maurice ) Five ! - ( thudding )
- ( Maurice ) Six ! - ( thudding )
( groans )
Oh , a man now , are ya ?
( coughs ) A man now , are ya , boy ?
You can 't fight me .
( Maurice laughs )
Can you feel that , boy ? ( laughs )
( laughs )
( laughs louder )
( neck snaps )
Subtitles : BTI Studios